We want to provide the dimensions that we're going to
下个任务是判断奇异值分解后
get for singular value decomposition.
获得的矩阵的维度
So, using what we know from the last videos,
根据从上个视频学到的知识
U remember is a matrix that's going to hold the number of
U 矩阵的行数等于用户数量
users as the rows and then the number of latent features as the column,
列数等于潜在特征的数量
and then sigma is going to be a square matrix,
∑ 是一个方矩阵
where the number of rows equals the number
行数等于列数
of columns equals the number of latent features,
并且等于潜在特征的数量
and then V transpose is going to
V 转置矩阵的行数
be the same number of rows as the same number of latent features,
等于潜在特征的数量
and then the number of columns is going to be the number of movies we're interested in.
列数等于电影数量
So, the number of rows is going to be the same as the number of users,
U 的行数等于用户数 答案是 b
b, the number of columns of U is the number of latent features,
U 的列数等于潜在特征的数量 答案是 a
so a, and the number of rows and V transpose,
V 转置的行数...
importantly, V and V transpose are going to have the opposite dimensions.
注意 V 和 V 转置的维度是相对立的
So, the number of rows and V transpose is
所以 V 转置的行数
going to be the same as the number of latent features,
等于潜在特征的数量
and then the columns are going to be equal to the number of movies.
列数等于电影数量
So, hopefully you can get a mental picture of
希望你能根据上个视频
that idea based on what we saw in the previous video.
在脑海中想象出这些关系
So then, next I want us to actually perform
接下来将对这个用户-电影矩阵
singular value decomposition on this user movie matrix,
执行奇异值分解
and they give us some documentation.
这里有一些文档
There's an example down here.
下面有个示例
I'm actually just going to pull this where a is the matrix that we do this,
我将复制这行代码 a 是要分解的矩阵
and this is called user_movie_subset.
改成 user_movie_subset
And so then, what you notice about the shapes of
你发现矩阵的形状有什么特征吗？
your matrices if you try to take the dot product of three objects you get back,
如果对获得的三个对象执行点积运算
can you directly do this to get back to user movie matrix?
能够直接获得用户-电影矩阵吗？
So notice, this is a four-by-four,
这是 4x4
this is a 20 by 20,
这是 20 x 20
and this is a four dimensional array.
这是一个四维数组
So, we can't take the dot product of these things.
我们不能对它们进行点积运算
Instead, they're being constrained by the number of movies in our matrix, right?
它们受到矩阵中电影数量的限制
So, this first one,
第一个矩阵
the sigma is actually just showing up as an array.
∑ 显示为数组
But what we really know is that that array is probably the diagonal elements.
我们知道该数组很有可能是对角线元素
This is the user matrix,
这是用户矩阵
so this is a 20 by 20 matrix where basically the number of columns
它是一个 20 x 20 矩阵
we want to keep is the number of latent features we want to keep,
列数等于潜在特征的数量
and then the maximum number of latent features we can keep is four because it's
能够保持的最大潜在特征数量是 4
constrained by the minimum of the number of movies or the number of users.
因为它受到电影数量和用户数量这二者的更小值的限制
So, here you can read my thoughts on that.
这些是我的思路
What we'd like to do is change
我们需要更改形状
the right shape so that we can actually take the dot product.
这样才能进行点积运算
So, what that means is,
所以 U 应该是 20 x 4
you should be a 20 by 4 because that's what they want k to be,
因为 k 应该是 4
which we can create in the following way.
下面说说创建方式
So, we want all of the rows,
我们需要所有的行
but we want the columns to be the same as the length of s. So,
但是列数等于 s 的长度
we're going to keep through the beginning through the fourth, which is the length of s,
我们将保留第 1 列到第 4 列 即 s 的长度
and then s we want to actually be a diagonal.
s 应该为对角线矩阵
So, that's something we could do since we're keeping all four of them,
我们将保留所有 4 个值
we can just store the diagonal.
所以直接存储该对角线矩阵
Then, the last thing we want to do is get V transpose,
最后获取 V 转置矩阵
which is actually going to stay the same because it's already a four-by-four.
它将保持不变 因为已经是 4 x 4 矩阵
So, if we look at this, then we look at the shape,
我们来看看形状
the idea is that it's a 20 by 4 and then we're going to
它是 20 x 4
multiply that by this thing which is a four-by-four.
然后乘以这个 4 x 4 矩阵
So, let's do s_new.shape and then vt_new.shape.
s_new.shape 然后是 vt_new.shape
All right. And if we look at this,
好的看看这些矩阵
now we have this 20 by 4,
这个是 20 x 4
which is our user by latent feature and then this is our sigma matrix,
即用户 x 潜在特征 这个是 ∑ 矩阵
which is a four-by-four,
它是 4 x 4
and then this last,
最后一个是
which is just the number of latent features by the number of latent features,
潜在特征的数量 x 潜在特征的数量
and then this is the number of latent features by the number of movies.
这个是潜在特征数量 x 电影数量
But if we wanted to, we could change this so that it's like three latent features,
也可以改成 3 个潜在特征
and then a three-by-three,
变成 3 x 3
and then a three-by-four is possible,
然后是 3 x 4
or if we wanted two latent features.
还可以改成 2 个潜在特征
But again, the number of latent features is
潜在特征的数量
constrained by the minimum of the number of users and the number of movies.
受到用户数量和电影数量这二者的更小值的限制
So, in this case, it's constrained by four.
在此示例中受到 4 的限制
Then it looks like we got all of that right.
看起来一切都正常
Now we are being asked,
接下来的问题是
what's the total amount of variability in our data set that we can try to explain?
我们能够解释的数据集总变化量是多少？
We can actually get that by taking the sum of the diagonal elements squared.
获得方法是计算对角线元素的平方和
The next question is,
下个问题是
what's the variability explained by component one and component two?
第一个和第二个分量能够解释多少变化量？
So, we can take the first element squared plus the second element squared.
我们可以计算第一个元素的平方加上第二个元素的平方
So, this gives us the total amount of variability explained by the first two components,
这就是前两个分量解释的总变化量
and then the percentage is then this far explained component divided by the total.
百分比等于这两个分量的变化量除以总变化量
So, the total amount of variability in the original matrix is this amount,
原始矩阵的总变化量是这么多
and actually the first two components explain quite a bit of it.
前两个分量所占的百分比很高